Senior .Net Developer

Personal Information

Full Name Sina Mohammadpouri Naeim

Date of Birth 05nd December 1978

<u> pournaeim@gmail.com</u>

+989354558317

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sina-pournaeim-10337639

https://github.com/CyberneticCode/Multilingual-WebShop



About

My activities include

- 13 years of experience working as a Software Designer and Developer.
- A senior developer and an elementary architect of software solutions based on Microsoft .NET
 Platform. I am a punctual and helpful person in a team, additionally, I am available in crisis work
 situations and can stay calm in a work crisis. In fact, I love software development, I really want to
 be one of those people who can make a big difference in the software design industry.

Work Experience

Senior Software Developer

At BICT CO. Part time, remote

Feb 2019 - Present, USA, California (remote)

- Develop, sort out difficulties and optimization of Contest system with ASP.net MVC
- Refactoring 30% of project to maintain compatibility to fundamental project changes due to Covid-19 pandemics

Full Stack Developer

As a Freelance.

May 2018 - Feb 2019, Tehran, Iran

- Revamped a program to transfer patient symptoms from an ECG device to a website with a student studying in New Mexico.
- Innovated creative bio lingual web-shop management with ASP.net MVC 5
 - The ability to add, update and delete any languages by web site manager without reprogramming and **100**% reduction in programming costs to add new languages
- Implemented journal paper management system with ASP.net MVC 5 at Azad University
- Designed and implemented validating and guiding passengers with ASP.net Web-Forms

Senior Software Developer

At Global media group IVS Co.

Sep 2017 - Feb 2018, Denmark (remote)

Design, Develop, and basic architecture of software systems with ASP.net MVC 5

Mid-Level Software Developer

At Tarh Pardaz Jolge Co.

- Prepared transfer system for the department of Education with ASP.net Web Forms
 - Teachers can upload their information on site for transferring to another city
- Developed monitoring system, identifying hardware and software data with ASP.net
- Improved performance of a financial reporting system for CNG with .Net Framework App
- Analyzed and facilitated and speed up the process of the Soldier division system
 - Due to the transformation of the Microsoft Word letters into Borland C++ report format, the process duration was cut from 4 days to 3 hours, making the division process 400% faster.

Junior Software Developer

At Pooyesh Barg Data Processing CO.

Jul 2007 - Feb 2011, Tehran, Iran

- Developed Water and Wastewater Organization web project with ASP.net Web Forms
- Being active learning at the beginning of each project
- Getting a promotion after creating a Helpdesk program to improve collaboration in team
 - A LAN-based internal chat application was implemented to speed up response times for team members and restructure communication flow among 16 teammates' requests; this reduced noise caused by verbal responses and requests at work by 90%.

Skills

- Languages
 - o C#, C++, JavaScript
- Technologies and Tools and Frameworks
 - o Windows Service, Web Service, Web API 2
 - ADO.Net, Entity Framework, ASP.NET Web Forms , ASP.NET MVC, ASP.Net Core ,SQL Server
 - o HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap, Telerik Rad Controls, Stimulsoft Report Designer
 - Microsoft Visual Studio, TFS, Git
 - o Game Programming with Unreal Scripting, Elementary DirectX,
- Methodology of analysis and Implement
 - o OOP, Basic Software Architecture
 - Agile thinking
 - o SOLID Principles

Education

Bachelor in Software Engineering

Azad University of Lahijan Jan 2001 - May 2005

Languages

• Persian: Native, English: Intermediate, Turkish: Upper Intermediate

Interests

Soccer, Tennis, Badminton, Yuga and Neuroscience, Sci-fi movies, Nature and Galaxy

Licenses & certifications

• Basic of Neuroscience Shahid Beheshti University of Medical Sciences Issued Jul 2019 No Expiration Date